(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-09T06:18:36.366438",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
割り切る前に黙った
I shut up before I gave in,
傷付く前に笑った
laughed before I got hurt,
拗ねる前に地団駄
stomped before I pouted,
流される前に辞めたんだ
gave up before I got swept away.
お守りみたいな
Like a protective charm,
ごく僅かな共通点の
scraps of the slightest common ground
端っこだけ握りしめて
tightly clutched at the edge.
今日接取した夕食も
The dinner I partook today,
昼休みを覆う仕草も
the habit of covering lunch break,
知りたい欲求ぶらさがって
hanging on desire to know,
偶像の中で探してたんだ
I searched among my idols.
これまでにない感覚
A sensation like never before,
強く攻め込まれる
strongly attacking me—
人類なんだしー
we're human after all,
自由自在のはずが
we should be free to do as we please,
お利口な素振りで
but acting like good kids,
味のしない
it's tasteless.
心肺専用
Dedicated to heart and lungs,
動悸が加速する
my palpitations accelerate.
ルールは
Rules are
終わりを
what announce
告げるものでしょ
the end, aren't they?
全身演じきってよ
Act it out with your whole body!
全開でその程度?
Is that all you've got at full throttle?
不器用で優しいだけでは越えられないです
You can't get through just being clumsy and kind.
見栄張ってんじゃない?
Aren't you just putting on airs?
ちゃんとせい
Get it together!
what's your pain?
感情戦を君と練っていきたいんだよ
I want to plan emotional battles with you.
萎えるぜ全方位
It's exhausting in all directions,
急にだるいよ
suddenly feeling so sluggish.
君専用の心構えしかないけれどぱっぱと参ろ
With only a mindset for you, let's march quickly.
信じたいよ
I want to believe,
待ち伏せたいよ
I want to lie in wait,
お帰りって
saying "welcome back",
お参りして退散
visiting shrines and retreating,
大事にたいだ談
making a big deal out of idle chat.
ランバダ
Lambada,
怠惰だ
so lazy,
countdown
壊れるのは呆気ない
Breaking down is so anticlimactic,
だんだん返事が素っ気ない
replies gradually growing curt.
暮れゆく方面走って
Running towards the setting sun,
失って気づくの冷たいじゃないか
realizing only after losing how cold it is.
お守りみたいな
Like a protective charm,
ごく僅かな共通点の
scraps of the slightest common ground,
端っこどこに忘れたの
where did you forget the edges?
不安定構造エンドレス
Unstable structure, endless,
手に入れれば雑に扱って
once we get it, we treat it carelessly,
わざわざ居なくなってみたり
intentionally disappearing sometimes.
かくれんぼたまには
Hide-and-seek every now and then
大事だと思う
I think is important.
自分を守る念力
The psychic power to protect myself
ばかり強くなるけど
just keeps getting stronger, but...
人類なんだしー
we're human after all,
自由自在のはずが
we should be free to do as we please,
お利口な素振りで
but acting like good kids,
味のしない
it's tasteless.
心配せんよ
Don't worry,
動悸が加速する
my palpitations accelerate.
ルールは
Rules are
終わりを
what announce
告げるものでしょ
the end, aren't they?
全身演じきってよ
Act it out with your whole body!
全開でその程度?
Is that all you've got at full throttle?
不器用で優しいだけでは越えられないです
You can't get through just being clumsy and kind.
見栄張ってんじゃない?
Aren't you just putting on airs?
ちゃんとせい
Get it together!
what's your pain?
感情ないときこそ問いただすんだよ
It's when you have no feelings that you should ask.
(萎えるぜ全方位 急にだるいよ)
(Exhausting in all directions, so sluggish)
何もやってないくせに言い訳ばっか口にするなよ
Don't make excuses when you've done nothing!
(信じたいよ 待ち伏せたいよ)
(I want to believe, to lie in wait)
お帰りって お参りしては 疲れ果てて眠りたい
Saying welcome back, visiting shrines, just wanting to sleep
けど放っておけない事態 怠惰談
but a situation I can't ignore, idle talk.
おお、始まりましたね
Oh, it has started.
始まりましたね
It has started.
どうも白神フブキです
Hello, I'm Shirakami Fubuki.
星街すいせいです
And Hoshimachi Suisei.
いやぁ、とりあえずなんかね、みこさんに呼ばれて我々スタジオに来ましたけど
Well, Miko-san called us and we came to the studio, but...
うん
Yeah.
なんかみこっちいない
Somehow Miko-chii isn't here.
いないし何にも聞かずにやってきた
We came without hearing anything at all.
この白い空間、まっしろすぎるだろ
This white space... it's way too white!
白いよだって
It's white, yeah.
白いよ
It's white.
みこさん!
Miko-san!
あ、もう同化した
Ah, she already assimilated.
あれ、いろいよ!
Huh? She's here!
ふぶさんだから、いるよここに、バカ野郎!
Fubu-san, she's right here, you idiot!
あの、すいません
Um, excuse me.
あ、あの、いしか
Ah, um, is that so?
そろそろ
It's about time.
あ、なんか声がする、天の声。
Ah, I hear a voice, a heavenly voice.
あの、二人ともね、あ、座っていただいてね、
Um, both of you, please take a seat,
あ、ありがたいね。
Ah, how kind.
あ、じゃあちょっとあの、Vフリ?
Ah, then, um, a V-preview?
あ、なんかある、Vフリね、あ、Vがあるんだ
Ah, there's a V-preview, oh, there's a V.
じゃあ一緒にどうするか。あ、わかりました。
Then what shall we do together? Ah, understood.
せーの、どうぞ!
Ready, set, go!
2018年
世間が藤井聡太プロの史上最年少7段昇進に沸く中
Amidst the public excitement over Sota Fujii becoming the youngest pro to reach 7th dan,
彼女は産声をあげた
she let out her first cry.
はい、ということで、にゃっはろー!
Yes, and with that, Nyahalloo!
名はさくらみこ
Her name is Sakura Miko.
電脳桜神社の巫女 アイドルVTuberだ
A virtual shrine maiden of Cyber Sakura Shrine, an idol VTuber.
人はさくらみこをこう呼ぶ
People call Sakura Miko this:
エリート
Elite.
愛らしいルックス
Adorable looks,
等身大のキャラクター
a down-to-earth character,
独特の声色を武器へ
turning her unique voice into a weapon—
熱狂は海を超えた
her enthusiasm crossed the sea.
スターへの階段を一気に駆け上がるさくらみこ
Sakura Miko rapidly climbs the stairs to stardom.
デビュー当初は… みこのファンの人って全然いなかったの
But in the beginning... nobody was really a fan of Miko.
アイドルになりたい ちゃんと頑張りたい 「悔しい」ってね実感したんです
I wanted to be an idol, I wanted to try my best... I truly felt so frustrated.
悔しさを糧に 誰よりももしのび 耐え続けた極貧生活
Fueled by that frustration, she endured a life of extreme poverty, persevering more than anyone.
そんな痛みも持ち前の明るさで乗り越えてきた
She has overcome all that pain with her natural brightness.
そして今夜 新たなステージへと導く 重大発表が
And tonight, a major announcement leads her to a new stage.
みこが走馬灯の時に絶対に出てくる すごい思い入れのあるものになるんじゃないかなって人生の中でね 思いますよ。
I think in my life, this is something that will definitely appear when my life flashes before my eyes, something I care about deeply.
さくらみ子の人生に刻まれる 新たな1ページが今夜明かされる
Tonight, a new page carved into Sakura Miko's life will be unveiled.
風の中のすばる
In the wind, the Pleiades,
砂の中の銀河
in the sand, the Milky Way.
みんな何処へ行った
Where did they all go?
見送られることもなく
Without even a send-off.
草原のペガサス
In the fields, Pegasus,
街角のヴィーナス
on the street corner, Venus.
みんな何処へ行った
Where did they all go?
見守られることもなく
Without even being watched over.
地上にある星を誰も覚えていない
No one remembers the stars on earth,
人は空ばかり見てる
people only look at the sky.
つばめよ高い空から教えてよ 地上の星を
Swallows high in the sky, tell me of the stars on earth!
つばめよ地上の星は今 何処にあるのだろう
Swallows, where are the stars on earth now?
エリートみこ 激動の6年 〜今夜DAI DAI DAI 大発表〜
Elite Miko's Turbulent 6 Years ~Tonight: DAI DAI DAI Major Announcement~
さあ改めて始まりました プロジェクトM エリートの流儀
Now, Project M: The Elite Way has begun anew,
司会進行をする白上フブキと 星街すいせいです
hosted by Shirakami Fubuki and Hoshimachi Suisei!
いやとんでもなくドラマチックに始まりましたけどこれあの番組ですよね完全にね
Man, that started off insanely dramatically, but this is totally that show, right?
そうですね
That's right.
これあのちょっと私もですねお世話になっておりますあの曲の…
I've also been looked after by that... that song...
あの曲
That song,
そうでしょうね
exactly.
なんかね歩いてます
She was walking, somehow.
ねぇなんだろねあれ
Yeah, I wonder what that was.
記憶がないです歩いた記憶が
I have no memory of walking.
こんな風に歩いてた記憶が
Memories of walking like this...
こんな風に歩いとったし なんか
She was walking like this, and like...
え、むずっ！ ASMRっぽい感じしましたけども面白かったですね
Huh, difficult! It felt like ASMR, but it was interesting.
まぁこの後何か重大発表があるらしいですね
Well, it seems there's a major announcement after this.
あぁそうなんですね
Ah, is that so?
なんかもう後ろにもう出てるね これ何なんですかこれ
It's already showing up behind us. What is this?
なんかちょっと気になるものがでておりますけれども
Something a bit concerning has appeared.
まぁね気になるこなんですが主人公をお呼びします
Well, it's something to be curious about, but let's call our protagonist.
はい
Yes!
どうぞー！
Go ahead!
みなさん にゃっはろーです
Nya-hello, everyone!
どうも エリートさくらみこです
Hello, I'm elite Sakura Miko.
本日はお集まりいただき どうもありがとうございます
Thank you all so much for gathering here today!
どうもね いや感動的だったな
Thank you. Man, that was touching.
お主、お主って言っちゃった。お主さ、エリートって言う割にはさ、なんか…
You called me "onushi" (lord/thou). For someone who calls herself elite, you're kind of...
なに和風なんですか
What's with the Japanese style?
座り方がちょっと偉そうですね これ
Your seating posture looks a bit arrogant, doesn't it?
本当だよ 偉そうじゃん
Truly, you look arrogant.
今日はね もうDAI DAI DAI重大発表だからね うんなるほど
Well, today is a DAI DAI DAI major announcement, so... yeah, I see.
もうこのくらいの もうすごい持ち上げてくれたでしょねえ
You lifted me up so much around this level, right?
なんかすごかったよね
It was amazing, wasn't it?
みこ とんでもないなと思ってさ なんかちょっと気持ちよかったというかもうありがたかったよね
I thought Miko is incredible, it felt a bit good, and I was so grateful.
あでもよかったよね
Ah, but it was great.
なんか「あっちゅ！あっちゅ！アエンビエン」とか言われる年とかね なんかあったね
Like years when people said "Atchu! Atchu! Aenbien" and stuff, there were those times.
あれはちょっと、ん？お、お？となったけど あれ、誰なの？あれ編集したのって誰なの？ わかんない
That made me go "Hmm? Oh, oh?", but who was that? Who edited that? I have no idea.
ちょっと今ごろちょっとね あそこらへんで…
Right around now... around there...
笑ってんの？ 笑ってんの？
Are you laughing? Are you laughing?
笑ってる人がいますけれども
There are people laughing over there, though.
これなんかちょっと
This is kind of...
なんであの番組のパロディにしてしまったんですか？
Why did you make it a parody of that show?
やっぱ壮大さん
Well, Soutai-san...
あ、壮大さんで
Oh, Soutai-san?
やはりすごいなと思って
I thought, "Wow, that's amazing."
あとやっぱさ、もうこの重大発表って、物をするなら…ああいう感じのなんていうの、もう…
And also, you know, for a major announcement, if you're gonna do it... something like that, you know...
すごいんだよっていうところをさ
Like, showing how incredible it is!
すごくない？ここまでアホっぽくできるの？すごいよね
Isn't it amazing how goofy this can be? It's amazing, right?
めちゃすごいんだよ。何一つ伝わんなかったけど、この発表に関しては
It's so amazing! Not a single thing got across about this announcement, though!
ま、ただただすごいなっていうのは本当にあのナレーターの大川…そう、大川さんの声が声でさ。
But honestly, just saying it's amazing—really, the narrator Okawa... yes, Okawa-san's voice.
あれはすごかったね。みこも本当に感動でね
That was amazing. Miko was truly moved, you know.
もう本当にね、もうなんかありがたい極みでございます。そのエリートだなんて。そんな、そんな、そんな。
I'm truly filled with gratitude. To call myself "elite"... No way, no way, no way!
ということで、みこさんの後ろにね
And so, behind Miko-san...
よくわかんないですけど大年表があるので
I don't really know, but there's a big timeline,
ここからはね、みこさんの歴史を振り返っていきたいなと思いますよ。
so from here, we'd like to look back at Miko-san's history.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much!
じゃ、まず2018年で見ていきましょうか。
Well then, let's start by looking at 2018.
2018年の5月1日に
On May 1st, 2018,
X初投稿
first X post,
そして8月1日から結構空いて
and after quite a gap, starting August 1st...
3カ月空いて8月1日から結構空いてんだね。
A 3-month gap, and starting August 1st... It's quite a gap, huh?
ホントのデビューがね、ここからの話なんだ けど
The real debut, you know, that's the story from here onwards, but...
デビューはやっぱりさくらみこなんかさ、春に…デビューしたいじゃん。さくらが咲いてる頃に。
Miko wanted to debut in spring, you know. When cherry blossoms are blooming.
だ けど、大人の事情でダメだったんだよ。
But due to adult circumstances, it didn't work out.
だから8月になったのも知ってたよね、さくらは。
So Sakura knew it became August.
じゃあほんとは5月にデビューしたかったの？
So you actually wanted to debut in May?
そう。5月っていうかもっと前に、もっとデビューしたかったけど
Yes. May, or rather even earlier, I wanted to debut sooner, but...
まあ、大人の、なんだろう、だから難しいよね。
Well, adult... how should I put it, so it's difficult, right?
難しい事情、そうだよね。
Difficult circumstances, yeah.
この時代って特にね、今よりもっと難しい。もっと難しかった。
Especially in this era, it was even harder than now. Even harder.
私もね、この2018年の3月ですから、デビューが。そう だよね。
I also debuted in March 2018, so... That's right.
私の方が先輩なんで。先輩なんで。
I'm the senior here! As a senior!
あの、敬っていただけてもよろしいです。
Um, you can show some respect, you know.
いや、でも今日は違うから。みこさん主役だからね。
Well, but today is different. Miko-san is the main character!
そしてその1年の、25日クリスマスにホロライブ加入。そうなんです、半 年ぐらい空いて、ついに、という感じでね。
And then, on December 25th (Christmas) of that same year, joining Hololive. That's right, after about half a year, finally—that kind of feeling.
まあ、おじしてね。
Well, grandly making our move.
まあ、おじしてっていうか、まあ、元々ね、色々あったんだよね。
"Grandly," or rather, well, originally there were various things.
ちょっと端折っていかないとまだまだありますからね。
We gotta hurry along or there's still a lot more!
オリ曲もきまして、2周年きまして。
Original song came, 2nd anniversary came.
ああ、さくら風もありましたね。ありましたね。
Ah, "Sakura Kaze" happened too. It did, it did.
そして7月19日、みこメット結成。
And on July 19th, Micomet formed!
ということでね、あの、4周年おめでとうございました。
So, um, congratulations on your 4th anniversary!
なんかやりましたね。
We did something, yeah.
初期はお互い、あの、2人と絡みがあったんだけど、なんかすごいギクシャクしてたんだよね、昔は。
In the early days, the two of us interacted, but it was super awkward back then, you know.
え、だってさ…
I mean, because...
うえー！
Ugh—!
お前、やめろよ！
Hey, stop that!
おい、待て、ふぶさん、そこ掘り下げないでよ！
Hey, wait, Fubu-san, don't dig into that!
バカ、記憶出てないよ！出てないの！
Idiot, the memories aren't coming out! They aren't!
もう何の記憶もないから今。ケチらせないでよ！
I have no memories of it now! Don't be stingy!
何もない！
Nothing at all!
初期のみこメット消し去らないでよ！
Don't erase early Micomet!
もう知らない。
I don't know anymore.
一旦初期はね、ちょっと置いといたよね。
Once, early days... we sort of put them aside, right?
あ、置いといた。もう4周年でも全てを浄化させたから、もう終わり。
Oh, we put them aside. By the 4th anniversary, we purified everything, so it's over!
ああ、でもこれからの、みこメットは？
Ah, but from here on, Micomet is...
これからの、みこメットは、まあ、変わらずね、ビジネスで。ビジネスですから。
From here on, Micomet is, well, unchanged—it's business! It's business, so.
なるほどね。
I see.
そして2021年に
And then, in 2021,
1stソロライブありまして。
our 1st solo live took place.
そして8月30日、100万人突破！
And on August 30th, breaking 1 million subscribers!
突破したね。2021年なんだね。
We broke it. It was 2021, huh.
ねー！
Yeah!
そして2021年の1大ニュースも100万人より1大ニュースね、12月16日「運命の改札」！
And the biggest news of 2021, even bigger than 1 million: on December 16th, "Unmei no Kaisatsu"!
運命の改札が
"Unmei no Kaisatsu"...
いやー、なんだこれ。これって3年前だったんだ。
Man, what is this? This was 3 years ago?
そうなんだよね。なのにあんなに擦られてるのまだ…
That's right. And yet it's still being brought up so much...
去年とかの話だと思っててよ、もう。
I thought it was a story from last year or something!
いや、まさかのね、だってあれはもうだってね…
No way, I mean, because that's already...
マップさんがね、反応してしまったから。マップさんがね。
Moomoo-san reacted to it! Moomoo-san did!
マップさん見てる？
Are you watching, Moomoo-san?
見てるよ！待ってるよ！
She's watching! She's waiting!
え、ということはもしやこの重大発表の、あの、マップさんから見ですか？
Wait, does that mean this major announcement is... from Moomoo-san's perspective?
あ、違う違う違う違う。
Ah, no, no, no, no!
違う違う違う！
No, no, no!
噂されてはいたけど違うの。
It was rumored, but that's not it.
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, is that so?
なんだ。
What is it, then?
そして2022年に、12月…12月色々あるね。27日「ごもく並べ」。
And in 2022, December... December has a lot of things. On the 27th, "Gomoku Narabe".
そういう時期なのかな。
I guess it's that kind of season.
そうだね、ごもく並べ 12月にあったんだね。
That's right, "Gomoku Narabe" was in December.
あ、そう だね、ふぶさんとの。
Ah, right, with Fubu-san.
ありましたね、あれね、奇跡的な。
That happened, that miraculous thing.
ちなみにですけど、
By the way,
あの、最近ね、言ったんですよ、すいさんに。
um, recently I told Sui-san,
うん、やってましたね。
Yeah, she was doing it.
そしたらね、みこ買ったの！
And then, you know, Miko won!
どうでもいい、もうどうでもいいよね。じゃあ次、次ね。
Whatever, who cares anymore! Well, next, next.
はい、で、2023年に、なるとたい焼き本舗さんコラボがありまして。大好きなたい焼き屋さん とついにコラボという感じでね。
Yes, and in 2023, the collaboration with Narutotaiyaki Honpo happened. Finally collaborating with her favorite taiyaki shop!
大喜びでね、我が家にも運んできました。はい、もうみんなに運びましたから。
Overjoyed, she brought it to her own home too. Yes, she brought it to everyone!
運びたくないわけないわけ！
There's no way she wouldn't want to carry it!
おいじゃ食べようかな
Shall we go eat something?
芋のやつ食べたいなって言って
I said I wanted to eat potato stuff,
「わかった！」って言ってさくらんばっかり持ってきて
and she went 'Okay!' and brought only Sakura stuff,
芋なかったんだから！
when there wasn't any potato!
でもさくら美味しかったからな また食べたいな あれな
But Sakura's was so delicious, I want to eat it again.
そうだね ねえねえねえ
That's right! Right, right, right?
東京観光大使就任まりね！ありましたね！
Tokyo Tourism Ambassador appointment! That happened!
ありましたね！
That really happened!
ねえ、配達してた
Yeah, you were doing deliveries.
8月2日には1st EPが…あー！ありました！出ましたね！
And on August 2nd, the 1st EP... Ah! Yes! It came out!
で、もうこれも去年なんだ！ねえ、去年なんだね
And this was already last year! Right, it's been a year!
びっくり、もう1年経ったんだ
Amazing, a whole year has passed.
ね、あっという間だね、月日はね、ね、本当だね
Time flies, days go by so fast, really.
2024年2月22日に鳴門鯛焼本舗との第2弾のコラボ！
On February 22nd, 2024, our 2nd collab with Naruto Taiyaki Honpo!
ありましたね
That happened!
ニャンニャンのお日ね、ありがたいよ
On Cat's Day, how wonderful.
ありまして、そして4月9日に200万人突破で！
And then, on April 9th, passing 2 million subscribers!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
そして本日7月21日に、なんかダーダーダーが、なんかね、3つ続いてからの10大発表で、あの、こうやって見たらダダダダダダに...
And today, July 21st, after three 'Dai's in a row, our 10 major announcements—if you look at it like this, it's Da-Da-Da-Da-Da...
ってことですね、ははは
is what it is, haha.
何なんでしょうね、一体何の発表が控えているのか、楽しみではありますけども
I wonder what on earth it is, what announcements are waiting, I'm looking forward to it.
どうやって発表されるんです、これ？
How will these be announced?
いや、なんかどーって来る？今ちょっと教えていただきました、まだ教えてほしいんだけど
Well, like, will they just come? I was just told, I want you to tell me more.
まだやんないの？まだやるわけないじゃん！
Not yet? Of course not yet!
まだやんないの？まだまだじゃん！
Not yet? Not yet!
え？まだVTRあるんですか？
Eh? There's still a VTR?
VTRあるんだ！あれだけじゃありません。私んなそうだから
There's a VTR! That's not all of it.
あ、だからみこさんの紹介して終わりだけかと思ってた。まだありますよ！
Ah, I thought it was just introducing Miko and ending. There's still more!
そっか、色々と頑張りましたからねということで、色々頑張る
I see, we worked hard on various things, so...
ねえ、ちょっと実はね、密着ってちょっとロマンじゃない、みんな。ね、密着されてみたいだなと思うでしょ？
You know, actually, 'close-up tracking' is romantic, isn't it? Everyone wants to be tracked like that, right?
密着？どういう密着？
Close-up? What kind of close-up?
え、こうやってぎゅうぎゅうぎゅうって密着して、密着？
Like, pressing close together like this, close-up?
パパヤローだね。密着？え？違う違うそっちか。
Papayaro! Close-up? Ah, no, the other one.
あの、ほら、ちょっと今撮ってますよ、みたいな。あー映像的な！なるほど！密着してもらったんだ。
You know, like 'we're filming you right now'. Ah, video coverage! I see, you had a close-up documentary.
そのVがあるということで。
So that VTR exists.
え？どうなるの？え、みこさんの日常が見れちゃうってこと？
Eh? What happens? We get to see Miko's daily life?
みこさんの日常が今から見れるってこと？密着ってこと？もしかして今日そんな、そんなでもない、そんな十代発表が来るとと思ってらっしゃる？
You can see Miko's daily life from now on? A close-up? Do you think such major announcements are coming today?
わかんない、だって我々も聞いてないですから！とりあえずこれで進めてくださいって言われてるだけだからね。
We don't know, because we haven't been told either! We're just told to proceed with this.
まずシャープさんとのコラボじゃないんだって。そう、のりおたけやきほっぷさんもやったしね。
First of all, it's not a collab with Sharp. Right, we did Naruto Taiyaki Honpo too.
のみこさんの日常に密着してどうするんだっての。ねえ。みこさんの日常に密着してどうすんだっての。
What's the point of doing a close-up on Miko's daily life? Right.
ねえ。え？違うの？
Right? Eh? Is that wrong?
ちょっと待ってよ
Hold on a second.
いや、どうせダラしない日常を見せられるだけだもんね！もう、見おれはじめてなくなんの！そんな椅子に座ってんだよ。
Well, you're just gonna show us your sloppy daily life! I can't even look anymore! Sitting in a chair like that.
いやみんな同じ椅子に座ってるよ。
Hey, everyone's sitting in the same chair.
まぁまぁまぁ、分かりました。じゃあ、気になるな。
Well, well, understood. I'm curious.
あ、気になるかも！どんなVTRなんだろう！見たいな！みおれはじだ、VTR気になるな！見たいな！ダラくした毎日！イェーイ！ダラくした毎日！おなか出して寝てる毎日！
Ah, I might be curious! What kind of VTR is it! I want to see it! Mio-re haji da, I'm curious about the VTR! I want to see it! Slothful every day! Yay! Slothful every day! Sleeping with my belly out every day!
違うでしょ！違うでしょ！え？
That's not it! That's not it! Eh?
あれだよ、ホロみコメットさん、見て、これ3D初めてなんだよね。そうなんだよね。3人ではね。3人ではね。
It's Holo-Mi-Comet, look, this is our first time in 3D together. Right. The three of us.
え？じゃあみこちゃんのすごい日だよね！すごい日らしいよ。もっと褒めて、もっと褒めて。そしたらどうぞって言うわ。
Eh? Then it's an amazing day for Miko! Apparently an amazing day. Praise me more, praise me more. Then I'll say 'go ahead'.
すごいかも知れないな。元気ないな。
It might be amazing. You have no energy.
はーい！見たい！見たい！みこちのすごいとこ見たい！気になる！気になる！
Hooray! I want to see! I want to see Miko-chi's amazing side! I'm curious! I'm curious!
気になるは君のニューサンキン！イェーイ、ハローワールド！
Curious is your New Sankin! Yay, Hello World!
見たい見たい見たい！
I want to see, want to see, want to see!
え、これを見たらね、みこのこと見直しますよ。なるほど。
Eh, if you see this, you'll reevaluate Miko. I see.
それじゃあ、今日放出しようかな。お願いします。
Well then, shall I release it today? Please.
それじゃあ行きますよ！VTRご覧ください！うーん、VTRスタート！
Well then, here we go! Please watch the VTR! Mhm, VTR start!
エリートみこ、真の姿
[Elite Miko's True Form]
十大発表 密着初日
10 Major Announcements: Close-up Day 1
十大発表！
10 Major Announcements!
おはようございます。あ、おはようございます。
Good morning. Ah, good morning.
今日からだっけ密着？あ、どうぞどうぞ撮ってて
Is the close-up starting today? Ah, go ahead and film.
今何をされてたんですか？
What were you doing just now?
今は、あの十大発表の発表か、「大！大！大！」で悩んでて
Right now, I was worrying about the 'Announcements' in '10 Major Announcements', like 'Dai! Dai! Dai!'
「十大発表」って何ですか？
What are the '10 Major Announcements'?
十大発表は…うん、まだ内緒だね。
The 10 major announcements are... yep, still a secret.
サプライズ感 大事にしてっから
I make sure to keep a sense of surprise.
3Dライブのリハーサル
Rehearsal for the 3D live
歌う前のこだわりとかあるんですか?
Do you have any preferences before singing?
うまく歌えなくても愛嬌で頑張ろう
Even if I can't sing well, I'll do my best with charm!
歌は愛嬌でCOVER
Singing is about charm, COVER
今は何をしてるんですか?
What are you doing right now?
まあ体を清めてるみたいな
Well, purifying my body, sort of.
神を降ろしている 神を これが一番大事だ
Summoning gods... Summoning gods.
That's the most important part!
笑っていいとこなんだよね
You're supposed to laugh here, you know?
神を降臨させる儀式はどれぐらいかかる?
How long does the ritual to summon gods take?
3時間
Three hours.
巫女だからね 巫女だからね 桜みこ
Because I'm a shrine maiden.
Shrine maiden Sakura Miko!
名前覚えてる? ちょっとね、舐めてるね 舐めてる感じする
Do you remember my name?
You're kinda underestimating me.
新入り? 新入りです 舐めてるよ
A newcomer? I'm a newcomer.
You're underestimating me!
みこは何年にデビューしてると思う? 2019年? 2018年?
What year do you think Miko debuted? 2019? 2018?
2018年ですね
It's 2018.
これが伝説の0期生 え、本当にわかってなかったの?
Behold, the legendary 0th generation.
Eh, you really didn't know?
忘れたよ みこ どんな人に見える?
I forgot! What kind of person does Miko look like?
PONな人? PONな人 と?
A "PON" person? A "PON" person?
こうだよ
Like this!
みこさんは自分のことをどんな人だと思ってます?
What kind of person do you think you are, Miko-san?
見て! この草映して! これ1本1本頑張ってるでしょ? でも時に踏みつけられるでしょ? それでも頑張ってる みこそういう人
Look! Film this grass!
Each blade is working hard, right?
Even when trampled, they keep trying.
Miko is that kind of person.
雑草魂 笑うなよ
Weed spirit! Don't laugh!
うーんそろそろいい? みこ。この後もまだ2時間ぐらいあるんだよね
Um, is it about time? Miko, we still have about two hours after this, you know.
カメラ下げてもらっていい? はい、おい、おい
Could you lower the camera?
Hey, hey, hey!
エリート! エリートは誰? みこ! ありがとう みんなー!
Elite! Who is elite? Miko!
Thank you, everyone!
桜みこを体現する言葉 エリート
The words that embody Sakura Miko: Elite.
エリートと呼ばれるプレッシャーは? プレッシャー?
What's the pressure of being called elite? Pressure?
うーん感じなくなってきましたね なんかだんだん体が慣れてきたっていうか あまり感じなくはなってきたかなって
Hmm, I've stopped feeling it as much.
My body has gradually gotten used to it.
エリートじゃないみこって みこと言えないかなって
Miko without being elite...
Can I even call myself Miko anymore?
程遠い存在に1回なってみたいっすね なんか味わってみたいっていうか ポンコツの人いるじゃないですか? あれどうやってんだろって
I'd love to experience being a distant existence.
There are clumsy people, right?
I wonder how they do that.
みこさんも配信でよくPONするけど… えっ?
Miko-san also often has "PON" moments in her streams, but... Huh?
PONの時? 「PON」って思ってるもの全て エリートへと繋がる道だから、それは
At times of PON?
Everything you think is "PON"
is a path leading to being elite.
0点とるじゃないですか 10点取ったら「すげえ」ってなりますよね 常態に0点の人が10点取ったら
You know how you get 0 points?
If a 0-pointer gets 10 points,
people go, "Amazing!"
日頃PONやってるのはエリートと呼ばれるための種まきみたいなもんすよ もうそろそろ開花するんじゃない? エリート
Daily PON is seed-sowing to be called elite.
Isn't it about time it blooms? Elite!
桜みこどこがエリート?
Where is Sakura Miko elite?!
彼女をよく知る4人に話を聞いた
We asked four people who know her well.
どんな配信でも「ここは撮れ高だ!」と思うところがすごく分かるし、それを見て私たちもニッコリできる そこはすごくエリートだと思う
In any stream, she knows the content highlights,
and seeing that makes us smile too.
I think that's very elite.
エリートなのかどうかはちょっとわかんないですけれど
Whether she's elite or not,
I'm not really sure, though.
あれ?
Huh?
あの、本人い的には「エリートじゃない」って言って欲しいのか「エリートだよ」って言って欲しいのかどっちなんだろうなってずっと考えてて、同業者が「この子はエリートだよ」って言っちゃうと、その桜みこっていうキャラクターがね、ちょっと崩れていくというか、ね、だから「PON」って言ってあげた方がいいのか、どっちだよとも言えるので、合わせます ここは、はい。
I've wondered if she wants us to call her elite or not.
If peers call her elite, her character crumbles.
So should we call her PON? Either works, so I'll go along with whatever. Yes.
一般的な定義だと社会やグループの中で優秀とされる人間や集団あるいは社会やグループなのだで指導的支配的な役割を受け持つそうということだそうなのだめでまあどちらでしょうねうんみこさんはね優秀だとは思いますけど判断は難しいのでそちらで審議よろしくお願いします
Generally, elites hold leading roles in society.
So which is it? Miko-san is excellent, I suppose,
but since it's hard to judge, please decide over there!
過半数で、ノーエリート
By majority vote: Non-elite.
A majority without being elite,
そして今回の重大発表については
And as for this time's major announcement,
もっともっとみんなに知ってもらえて
I hope more and more people get to know about it,
これからの活動が飛躍するためのそういうイベントに
and that it will definitely be an event
絶対になると思います
that helps her future activities take off!
意味？
Meaning?
一言で言えないかも...
I guess I can't say it in one word...
素敵な出来物...出来事...
A wonderful event, or rather, occurrence.
このイベントはみこちのエリートの見せ所だと思います
I think this event is the real showcase of Miko's elite side.
とわいえ、あまり気負わずポンコツを見せつけたっていいと思います
That being said, rather than worrying, it's fine to show off her dorkiness.
実情、顧客のニーズはエリートではなくポンコツのさくらみこなのだで
After all, what the audience wants isn't an elite, but a clumsy Sakura Miko.
一つステップアップしていくような、あの、ファンの方をより楽しませるようなことができれば
to step up and entertain our fans even more.
隔世の感があるというか
It's almost like a whole different era.
今夜の重大発表を前に
Ahead of tonight's major announcement,
どうしても挑戦したいことがあるという
there was something Sakura Miko desperately wanted to challenge.
その場所が日本一なんですよ
That place is Japan's highest...
ま、そこに挑戦して羽ばたいちゃおうかなって
She decided to challenge it and spread her wings.
I can fly
彼女はそう言い残しある場所へと向かった
She headed off to a certain place with those very thoughts.
高さ日本一　岐阜バンジー
Japan's Highest: Gifu Bungee!
あの魚住さん約100人分の高さから飛び降り、重大発表に向けて覚悟を決めるのだという
Ahead of the major announcement, she chose to face this test of resolve,
また新たなスタートになると思います。一つの転換期。
marking a brand new start and a turning point.
どうしよう...怖えな～
What should I do? This is scary!
ちゃっちゃっときょうわと前に思い切りジャンプね？
A full-on jump right away?
うわー、一面緑だなー
Man, it's all green out here.
オーマイゴッド！本当に！
Oh my god! Seriously!
いや～、やばい！
Whoa, this is bad!
待って待って待って、待ってね。
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
オーマイゴッド！ノーノーノーノー、ノー！
Oh my god! Oh no no no no no! No!
ちょっと待って、足が動かない。
Wait, wait, wait, wait! My legs won't move!
誰か助けて！ちょっと一旦下へ座る。
Somebody help me! Let's sit down for a second.
戻る戻る。
Let's go back, go back.
恐怖のあまり足が前に出ない...
Overwhelmed by fear, her feet just won't step forward...
このまま飛ばずに終わるのか？さくらみこの決断は？
Is she really going to end this without jumping? What will Sakura Miko decide?
死なない？大丈夫だよね？叫ぶんだよね？ちゃんとジャンプするんだよね？
I won't die, right? It'll be fine, right? I just need to scream and jump, right?
オッケー！
Okay!
彼女には大切にしている一つの流儀があった。
She had one rule she held dear to her heart.
諦めない、心。
A heart that doesn't give up...
うわぁ～、怖い！
Whoa, so scary!
真っ直ぐ前向いて下を見ないで。オッケー、行きましょう。
Keep your eyes straight ahead, don't look down. Okay, let's go.
5、4、3、2、1、バンジー！
5, 4, 3, 2, 1, Bungee!
絶対成功させるぜ～！
I'm definitely going to make this a success!
うわぁ～！うわぁー！こわぁぁぁぁ～～っ！
Aaaaaah! So scary!
うわぁー！
Aaaaaah!
えっ！怖っ！うわぁぁぁ～！怖え～！
Hah, so scary!
はぁ…生きた…生き残ったよ
Haah... I'm alive... I survived!
生きててよかった。
I'm so glad I'm alive.
まだまだやりたいことって死ぬほどあるんだなって
I realized I still have so many things I want to do before I die,
こんなところで死んじゃダメなんだなって
and that I mustn't die in a place like this.
引き上げてもらう間 必死に生きるんだ生きるんだってすごい耐えてたの
While being pulled back up, I was desperately telling myself, "I'm going to live!"
何が引っ掛かった？
What got caught on you?
スタッフが追い込んだ？
Did the staff drive you to that point?
何やってくれとんねん！
What do you think you're doing?!
みこちゃんが死んじゃったかもしれないよ？かなりの損失だよ！
Miko-chan might have died! That's a massive loss!
自分で「やろう」って言ったんだけどね
I mean, I'm the one who said "Let's do it," but still...
枠にハマらないエリート
An elite who doesn't fit the mold,
信じた道を進む姿に心を動かされているのかもしれない
our hearts are moved by the way she walks her chosen path.
ミコにとってエリートは
For Miko, being elite...
諦めずに努力し続けて咲き誇る人
...is someone who never gives up, keeps working hard, and blooms proudly.
諦めそうになることたくさんありますからね
There are so many times you feel like giving up.
忘れられないぐらいツライことって後々の自分の糧になるというか
Painful experiences you can't forget become your nourishment later on.
出始めて全然ファンの人も少ない頃にバーチャルお渡し会があって
Back when I first started and had hardly any fans, we had a virtual hand-off event.
ミコのファンの人って全然いなかったの
There were practically no fans of mine there.
その時にミコ目当てで1人で来てくれたあれ救われたよね
But someone came all by themselves just for me, and that really saved me.
あれがあってミコアイドルになりたいちゃんと頑張りたいってまだまだ頑張りたいって
Because of that, I wanted to be an idol, to work hard, and to push even harder.
「悔しい」ってね実感したんです
That's when I truly felt what frustration was.
過去の自分がいたから今の自分がいられるってしんどいほど思うし
I feel so keenly that I'm who I am today because my past self was there.
ツライこともいっぱいあったけどそれが今のミコの味になってる
There were so many painful things, but they've become part of who Miko is now.
見てるかみんな！
Are you watching, everyone?!
すごいよ！
It's amazing!
でっかくなったな！
I've grown so big!
はーい
Yay!
あ、涙が出るねみんな
Ah, it's making us tear up, everyone.
あれ？あ、涙は出てないって
Huh? Ah, no tears are coming out, she says.
あ、涙、あ、出てないって
Ah, tears—ah, they're not coming out!
泣いてるよ！泣いてるよ！すごいよ！泣いてるよ！あれ誇らしいよ！
She's crying! She's crying! Amazing! She's crying! That's something to be proud of!
誇らしいよ！すごいかっぱ
So proud! Incredible, Kappa—
え？でも万次は頑張りましたね
Eh? But Banji did her best, right?
いや、やばい、怖すぎたんだけどあれVTuberで白上フブキに秒殺される
No, seriously, that was way too scary, getting one-shotted by Shirakami Fubuki as a VTuber—
え、でも万次は頑張りましたね
Eh, but Banji did her best!
いや、やばい、怖すぎたんだから
No, seriously, it was way too terrifying!
ＶTuberで白上フブキも振り切ってたじゃん
As a VTuber, Shirakami Fubuki was totally going all out too, right?
え、嘘だよ！高いとこんな！
Eh, no way! Up high like that!
なんで白上フブキ、なんでホロメン飛びたがんでよ、そんなさ、おかしいよ！
Why would Shirakami Fubuki—why do holomembers want to jump? That's just crazy!
え、なんかちなみにコツがあるんでしょ？
Eh, by the way, there's a trick to it, right?
コツ？
A trick?
そう
Yeah.
ホブコツ？
Hob-tricks?
頭から、あ、そうそうそう、こうやってね、こうやって立つでしょ？
From the head—ah, yeah, yeah, you stand like this, right?
うん
Yeah.
で、このまま足でぴょんって行ったら、もう一気にグワァンってなるわけだから怖いのよ
And if you just hop off like that, it suddenly rushes up, so it's scary!
こういう感じなの？
Is it like that?
そう、だから、あの何度もね教えてもらったんだけど、こうやってやって「山見て！山見て！」って言われて
Yeah, so I was taught many times, and they told me, 'Look at the mountain! Look at the mountain!'
山見て、こう行くの！こうやって！
Looking at the mountain, you go like this! Like this!
あ、こうやって行くんだ！
Ah, you go like that!
そう、こうやって行くの！おわ
Yeah, you go like this! Whoa—
なるほどね！
I see!
それはなおさら怖いです
That's even scarier!
いや、やばいですよ、やばいんだよ、本当怖いことなんだから！
No, it's dangerous, it really is terrifying!
今日、一応ね、色々頑張ってましたけどね
Well, today you worked hard on various things, though.
すごいねー
Amazing~
え、重大発表ってあの万次したってこと？
Eh, does the major announcement mean Banji did that?
なわけねぇだろが！
As if!
あ、違うんだ！
Ah, it's not!
それはさすがに…ホルマ等でね
That's naturally... streamed on Holomart or something.
ホルマ等でも流れる映像ですけどね
It's footage that airs on Holomart and stuff.
ホルマ等にも流れるけれど
It airs on Holomart too, but...
結局何なんですか？
What is it in the end?
ねぇ、なんか
Hey, like...
見てもわかんなかった？
Did you not get it even after seeing it?
全然わかんなかった
I had no idea at all.
本当？全然わかんなかった？
Really? You really didn't get it?
まだないしょ
It's still a secret.
なんだよ！
What the heck!
え、じゃあこの後何があるんだよ！
Eh, then what's coming up next?!
ええと、この後にはですね
Well, after this...
ミニライブがありまして
...we have a mini-live concert!
おお
Oh!
その後に
And after that...
発表すると
...we'll make the announcement.
おおー
Ooh!
ああ、緊張してきたー！
Ah, I'm getting nervous!
ミニライブって何歌うんですか？
What are you going to sing at the mini-live?
え、何って、何歌うっていうのは、まあ、ミコの曲だとか、まだね、あの、振り付け、まだね踊ったことない、みんなまだ踊ったことないやつとかが、すごい大変なんだよ！
Well, what am I singing? Things like Miko's songs, choreography I haven't danced yet, stuff nobody's danced yet—it's so hard!
こんなやつだ！こんなやつだ！
Like this! Like this!
あ、そうそう！
Ah, right, right!
これが来る？これが、これが来るのね？
Is this coming? This—this is coming?
あ、そうそう！
Ah, yeah!
あとは？
What else?
うん、いろいろ
Yeah, various things.
いろいろか！もう何でそんなね、これ読んだ方がいいって、この台本のこれ
Various things! Why don't you just read this script?
オーダー通り！
Right on cue!
ちなみに、はい！新曲も初披露します！
By the way, yes! We'll be premiering a new song too!
うわあ！新曲だ！新曲だね！
Whoa! A new song! A new song!
やったあ！
Yay!
わ、ということで、私たちの出番はじゃあこれで終わりだ。
Well, with that, our turn is over now.
え、そうだよ！
Eh, that's right!
出たらね！
Once we're out!
はい！すいみこメトさんでーす！
Yes! We are SuiMikoMeto!
とっていって、すいみこメトさん
Taking photos, SuiMikoMeto.
ねぇ、もうこれで終わっちゃうの、名残惜しいですけれど
Man, it's so sad that it's already ending.
本当だよ！
Totally!
ねぇ！これだと、教え、教えてほしい、我々もアイドルだからさ、重大発表教えてよ
Hey! Since we're idols too, tell us the major announcement!
せめてもう帰るからさ
At least before we go home.
しょうがないわ
Can't be helped.
二人でラーメン食べてくるからさ。そうだよ！
We're gonna go eat ramen together! That's right!
しょうがないわ。二人でラーメン食べてくるからさ
Can't be helped. We're going for ramen.
そうだよ！
That's right!
にゃこにゃこ、にゃにゃにゃ
Nyakonyako nyanyanya...
えっ？
Eh?
にゃやにゃやにゃ、マジで？マジで？えっ？本当に？
Nyayanyanya, seriously? Seriously? Eh? Really?
え、すいちゃんには？すいちゃんには？
Eh, what about Suichan? What about Suichan?
うわ！
Whoa!
にゃこにゃこ、にゃにゃにゃ…おい！すいちゃんやばいよ、これ！
Nyakonyako nyanyanya... Hey! Suichan, this is crazy!
すいちゃん、やばい！
Suichan, insane!
すいちゃん、そうそう！
Suichan, exactly!
まさか、まさか過ぎてやばい、あの、あのミコさんだよ！
It's so unbelievable it's crazy—it's, it's Miko-san!
えっ？もっと、もっと、お、おいおい！
Eh? More, more, hey hey!
ああ、そんな！
Ah, no way!
すいちゃん！まさか、まさか！
Suichan! No way, no way!
そんなことになってしまうのか！
Is it really going to turn out like that?!
ライブ行ってこい！
Go do your live!
そうだよ！っていうライブ
That kind of live!
じゃあ、ミコのね、あの、ライブ準備してきます！
Well then, I'll go get ready for my live!
はい！
Yes!
じゃあ、みんな楽しみにしててね！
Everyone, look forward to it!
いってらっしゃい！
Have fun!
いってきまーす！
We're off!
すごかったね！
That was amazing!
ねえ、まあ、ずっと頑張っていただきたいですね
Yeah, well, we hope you keep doing your best.
そうですね！
Indeed!
じゃあ行きますか、じゃあみこさんのライブでーす！どうぞー！
Shall we go then? Here is Miko-san's live! Go ahead!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！
Nya-Hello World!!!
さーゆこう！！！
Let's go!
えりーと舐めんな！
Don't underestimate the elite!
独壇場（はいっ！）
A solo stage! (Yes!)
配信だ！きょうも集まれーーー！！！
It's streaming time! Gather around today too!
箱庭で愛を！！！
Pour love into this miniature garden!
叫んで育て！このアホ毛（にゃっ！！）
Shout and nurture this ahoge! (Nya!!)
わがっつぁ！？→わがまんない！
Misunderstood? No, being selfish!
の繰り返し
Repeating over and over,
けど超越していくねぇぽんこつえれがんす
but transcending it with goofy elegance!
ポンな人生！！！
Such a goofy life!
えりーと！舐めんな！
Elite! Don't underestimate!
バチ当たるで
You'll bring bad karma upon yourself!
あんどう！？やんのかおまえら！！
What's that?! Wanna start something, you guys?!
飛んでみろオイ！
Try flying, hey!
＼みこ…！俺、恥ずかしいよ！／
\ Miko...! I'm so embarrassed! /
でゃまれっ！！！
Shut up!!!
叩き直したるねぇ！
I'm gonna set you straight!
そんな根性！（もーーっ！！）
Such grit! (No way!!)
＼みこ…！俺、恥ずかしいよ！／
\ Miko...! I'm so embarrassed! /
いまにみてなって
You'll see,
そのうち
before long,
マスターなオベレーション（大歓声）よ
I'll be a master of operation!
あ～ポンコツもやがて羽ばたくbutterfly！！！（ぱたぱた！！！）
Ah~ Even a goof will eventually spread her wings like a butterfly!!! (Flap flap!!!)
まいにち語録生み出したら！
If I keep creating quotes every day,
百人が無限色だーーー！！！
A hundred people will turn into infinite colors!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！さーゆこう！！！
Nya-Hello World!!! Let's go!
全35p！声上げろ～！（はいっ！）
All 35p! Raise your voices~! (Yes!)
＼みこち！みこち！／
\ Mikochi! Mikochi! /
きみにはきみの！乳酸菌なんて！！！
You have your own lactic acid bacteria and stuff!!!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！さーゆこう！！！
Nya-Hello World!!! Let's go!
えりーと舐めんな！独壇場（はいっ！）
Don't underestimate the elite! A solo stage! (Yes!)
配信だ！きょうも集まれーーー！！！
It's streaming time! Gather around today too!
箱庭を燃やそう！！！
Let's burn down this miniature garden!
真顔で使え！日用品！（にゃっ！！）
Use daily necessities with a straight face! (Nya!!)
思い出詰まったロケットは水がなくたって飛べるから！！！
A rocket packed with memories can fly even without water!
光ってほら！虹色だにゃ
Shine, look! It's rainbow-colored, nya!
ひとりずつ 名前呼ぶよ
I'll call your names one by one!
あえんびえん世知辛いけー！
Life is harsh and unforgiving, huh!
この治癒じゃ追うずみのみの身！
Trapped by these laws and security!
怨念全開ポンデミシック！
Grudges fully unleashed, pond-mythic!
悩めこついた頭もポンにして
Turn your troubled head into a goof too!
げけない！しょうがない！
Unstoppable! Can't be helped!
痛くないにゃ（待って待って～！！）
It doesn't hurt, nya (Wait, wait~!!)
あらんど世の中も（こらっ！！）
Even the chaotic world (Hey!!)
あきらめんな！
Don't give up!
心・筆が走らせるにゃ
Let your heart and pen run wild, nya!
＼みこ…！俺、誇らしいよ！／
\ Miko...! I'm so proud of you! /
これが大人よ！ホルモンまき散らせ！
This is what being an adult is! Scatter hormones everywhere!
＼みこ…！俺、誇らしいよ！／
\ Miko...! I'm so proud of you! /
てこい原理で人生もゾッコンでバッコンだにゃ！！！
Life is also totally head over heels with leverage theory!
玄人もやがて羽ばたくbutterfly！！！（つよつよ）
Even experts will eventually spread their wings like a butterfly! (Strong)
さあ言葉ごと生み出そう！
Now let's give birth to every word!
いま人生まっただなか～！！！
Right in the middle of life right now~!
あしたも歌おうこの場所
Let's sing here again tomorrow,
寂しい思いさせないよ
I won't let you feel lonely!
みこと！35p！
Miko and! 35p!
みんなでつくる独壇場なんに！！！
Building a solo stage together with everyone!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！さーゆこう！！！
Nya-Hello World!!! Let's go!
ちっちゃい身体！声上げろ～！（はいっ！）
Tiny body! Raise your voices~! (Yes!)
＼みこち！みこち！／
\ Mikochi! Mikochi! /
汗も滴るいい女なんて！！！
A fine woman with sweat dripping down her face and stuff!!!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！さーゆこう！！！
Nya-Hello World!!! Let's go!
えりーと舐めんな！独壇場（はいっ！）
Don't underestimate the elite! A solo stage! (Yes!)
配信だ！きょうも集まれーーー！！！
It's streaming time! Gather around today too!
箱庭で騒ごう！！！
Let's make noise in this miniature garden!
笑って挑めメンタルゲー！もっと遊べ！！！（にゃっ！！）
Smile and challenge the mental game! Play more! (Nya!!)
画面越しだってハイタッチ！目指せばなんだってなれるから！！！
High-five even through the screen! Because if you aim for it, you can become anything!
光ってほら！虹色だにゃ
Shine, look! It's rainbow-colored, nya!
いっしょに行こう ひとりずつ 名前呼ぶよ
Let's go together, I'll call your names one by one!
逃げない 告げない いたくないね
Won't run, won't confess, don't want to hurt!
アラウンダ世の中も あきらめんな
Don't give up on this all-around world either!
心の筆が走らせるね
Let the pen of your heart run wild!
生意気にひたり風邪ちゃって未来
Catching a cheeky chill in the future!
これが男だ！はるかうまく散らせ
This is a man! Scatter it far and wide brilliantly!
ここイキザマで！人生もドコでボコだね
With this way of life! Life is also bumpy and messy!
現人 もやがて羽ばたくbutterfly！！！
Even living humans will eventually spread their wings like a butterfly!!!
さあ言葉ごとみんなさ！
Now, everyone with every word!
いま人生の真っ只中 愛したもんは
Right in the middle of life right now, what you loved
この場所 そにしよもーそせないよ
I won't let you miss this place either!
みかこみかぴ みんなでつくる独壇場なんて！
Mikako, Mikopi, what a solo stage built together with everyone!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！さーゆこう！！！
Nya-Hello World!!! Let's go!
聞きたいから声上げよう！
Let's raise our voices because we want to hear you!
＼みこち！みこち！／
\ Mikochi! Mikochi! /
足を推したるいよだなんて！にゃっはろーわーるど！
Stuff like supporting your feet! Nya-Hello World!
さーゆこう！えりーと舐めんな独壇場！
Let's go! Don't underestimate the elite solo stage!
配信だ！きょうも集まれーーー！！！
It's streaming time! Gather around today too!
白羽が笑っていためめ！たのげもっと遊べ！
Even if Shiraha laughed, have fun and play more!
どこめんど臭くて入った決めず笑っちゃってのね
Deciding to enter even if it's a bit troublesome and just laughing it off!
ひかってほら！虹色だね
Shine, look! It's rainbow-colored!
ひとりずつ名前呼ぶよ ああいいんだね
I'll call your names one by one, ah it's good!
この日常も笑って羽ばたくbutterfly！！！
This everyday life also spreads its wings like a butterfly with a smile!!!
いつでもかてーりずつ名前呼ぶよ
I'll call your names one by one anytime!
いくよ？
Here we go?
きゅんきゅんみこきゅん？（きゅんきゅんみこきゅん！）
Kyun Kyun Miko Kyun? (Kyun Kyun Miko Kyun!)
きゅんきゅんみこきゅん！きゅんきゅんみこきゅん！
Kyun Kyun Miko Kyun! Kyun Kyun Miko Kyun!
キミにみこきゅん？
Miko Kyun to you?
きゅんきゅんみこきゅん♡（きゅんきゅんみこきゅん！）
Kyun Kyun Miko Kyun ♡ (Kyun Kyun Miko Kyun!)
ねぇ！あのねこれガチみんなトモダチ
Hey! You know, this is for real, everyone's a friend,
夢見るカタチでっかいぞ ぜっけー！まじ～！？
dreaming big, what a magnificent view! For real~!?
それはすなわち 成長中って話
That means we're still growing,
いろんなワタシ 超見て欲しい！
I want you to see all kinds of me!
エリートあいさつ！みんなにゃっはろ～！
Elite greeting! Nya-hello to everyone~!
エリートスマイル！ふっふっふ…きらーん☆
Elite smile! Heh heh heh... Sparkle☆
エリートダンス！みーみーみこみこっ！
Elite dance! Mi-mi-mikomiko!
エリートイングリッシュ！I'll be back!
Elite English! I'll be back!
まあね時にはにゃっ落ち込んじゃうこともあるよ
Well, sometimes we might get a bit down,
そんな時は はなまるあげるにぇ！
but at times like that, I'll give you a passing mark, nya!
｢おまえらよく聞きーーーい!!!!!｣
"You guys, listen up loud and clear!!!!!"
今日も一日 よくできました～！
You did a great job today too~!
はにゃっってふにゃっってほにゃっと混ぜたら
If you mix "hanya", "funya", and "honya",
キュンしちゃうから35チューン（みこきゅん！）
you'll fall head over heels, so a 35 tune (Miko-kyun!)
はやっぺにぴっぺぽよっすたらさいきょう!!!!
If you dash and pop and bounce, it's the strongest!!!!
うにゃうにゃしよう？ 一緒にせーの
Shall we go unya-unya? Together, on three—
ドキドキめろめろきゅん！（きゅんきゅん！）
Thumping, melting, kyun! (Kyun kyun!)
ぴょんぴょんめろめろきゅん？（きゅんきゅん！）
Bouncing, melting, kyun? (Kyun kyun!)
キラキラめろめろきゅん！（きゅんきゅん！）
Sparkling, melting, kyun! (Kyun kyun!)
きゅんきゅんみこきゅんきゅん！
Kyun Kyun Miko Kyun Kyun!
キミにきゅんをあげるよ
I'll give my kyun to you!
ねぇ！あのねこれガチほっぺはモチモチ
Hey! You know, this is for real, my cheeks are soft and mochi-mochi,
ミライのみこちすごい ぞっけー！まじ～！？
Miko-chi of the future is amazing, for real~!?
それはすなわち 邁進中って話
That means we're forging ahead,
それは必見だし超見て欲しい！
it's a must-see, so please look closely!
エリート拍手！パチパチパチパチパチ
Elite applause! Clap clap clap clap clap!
エリートジャンプ！ぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょん
Elite jump! Hop hop hop hop!
エリートおねえ！むにゃむにゃぐーぐー
Elite big sis! Mumble mumble snore snore!
エリートわがまま！やだ！やだ！うわぁぁぁんっ！(｡>ω<｡)
Elite selfishness! No! No! Waaaah! (｡>ω<｡)
だっていつでもありのままを伝えたいの… おまえらさぁ、みこを褒めんだりすんじゃねぇ～！ ふざけんなよぞーーーっ!!!!!!
Because I always want to convey my true self... You guys, don't go praising Miko and stuff~! Stop messing with me, nooooo!!!!!!
……って言えって言われましたーーっ！(;_;)
...is what I was told to sayーーっ！(;_;)
はにゃっってふにゃっってほにゃっと混ぜたら
If you mix "hanya", "funya", and "honya",
キュンしちゃうから35チューン（みこきゅん！）
you'll fall head over heels, so a 35 tune (Miko-kyun!)
はやっぺにぴっぺぽよっすたらてんさーい!!!!
If you dash and pop and bounce, you're a genius!!!!
うにゃうにゃしてもいいじゃない！せーの
Isn't it fine to go unya-unya? Ready, set—
ねぇねぇ あのねこれこじゅっ
Hey hey, you know, this is...
ぷにゅぷにゅ お手てはもちもち！
Squishy squishy, hands are so soft!
みんないのちのごちそう
Everyone's life feast!
すっごくてマジ
It's super amazing, seriously!
それすなわちマジって話
That means it's for real,
それは秘密だし超見て欲しい！
It's a secret, so I want you to watch!
じゃあ見て欲しい！
So please watch!
エリート拍手！
Elite applause!
パチパチパチパチ！
Clap clap clap clap!
エリートジャンプ！ ぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょん！
Elite jump! Hop hop hop hop!
のーみーた おねね！ むにゃむにゃぐーぐー！
Drinking sleep-ne! Munching and snoring zzz!
エリートわがまま！ やだやだやだ！
Elite selfishness! No way, no way!
だっていつだって あいのままを伝えたいの
Because I always want to convey my love just as it is!
お前らさ、みこを褒めてんじゃねー！！
Hey you guys, don't praise Miko!!
ふざけんなよーっ！！…って言えって言われましたーっ！！ (i_i)
Cut it out!! ...is what I was told to say!! (i_i)
ほニャってほニャってほニャって待ってたら吸収しちゃうからみこ中
If you keep waiting like "honya honya," Miko will absorb you!
ほニャってふにって酔ったら最後うにゃうにゃしてもいいじゃん
If you get drunk on "honya funi," it's fine to get all fuzzy!
せーの！ ピカピカみろみのるきゅんきゅん
Ready, set! Sparkling MiroMiro Lukyun kyun!
ふわふわみろみのるきゅんきゅん みなみなみろみのるきゅんきゅん きゅんきゅんみこきゅんきゅん
Fluffy MiroMiro Lukyun kyun, everyone's MiroMiro Lukyun kyun, kyun kyun Miko kyun kyun!
その今が宝物
That current moment is a treasure.
いつも愛をありがとう。
Thank you always for your love.
ここからはね、みこのカウントアップいってみっくねー！
From here on, let's do Miko's count-up!
はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
みんなコメントで愛のてんししてねー！
Everyone, send love in the comments!
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！うーいぇい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Oo yeah!
いつまでも いつまでも ずっとずっと 笑顔でいようね
Forever and ever, always and forever, let's keep smiling!
みこ頑張るよ！頑張れるよ！もっともっときゅんきゅんになってね
Miko will do her best! I can do my best! Get even more kyun-kyun!
ラストにもう一回張り切って～！みこちゃんは？エリートです！
For the last time, give it your all! Who is Miko-chan? An elite!
ほニャってほニャってほニャって待ってたら吸収しちゃうからみこ中
If you keep waiting like "honya honya," Miko will absorb you!
ほニャってふにって酔ったら最後うにゃうにゃしてもいいじゃん一緒に
If you get drunk on "honya funi," it's fine to get all fuzzy together!
せーの！ ドキドキみろみのるきゅんきゅん
Ready, set! Heart-pounding MiroMiro Lukyun kyun!
ぴょんぴょんみろみのるきゅんきゅん キラキラみろみのるきゅんきゅん
Hopping MiroMiro Lukyun kyun, sparkling MiroMiro Lukyun kyun!
みこきゅんきゅんみこきゅん きみにきゅんをあげるよ
Miko kyun kyun Miko kyun, I'll give you my kyun!
みんな！ まだまだ行くよ！
Everyone! We're still going!
思い出しかんだ
I remembered...
そっと涙した日を
The days when I quietly shed tears.
さあ数えてみようわがまま越えた奇跡を
Come, let's count up the miracles that overcame selfishness.
見てらんなく止まらない足で
With unwatchable, unstoppable feet,
膨らんでく夢の みつつながる絆は
The expanding bonds of dreams connected one by one...
キミと広げてきたかよ
Have spread out with you.
何度でも咲くよ 弱気に 続いてくこのストーリー
Blooming no matter how many times, timidly continuing this story.
まだ見たことのない景色を捜しに行こう
Let's go search for scenery we've never seen before!
花びら一つずつが 小さくてもほら 支え合えたら
Even if each petal is small, see, if we support each other,
桜になれるよ 僕らが繋いだ
We can become cherry blossoms! The big tree we connected
大きな木はまだ これからもはるか風に向かって
Will still face the distant wind from now on
伸びてくのさ
And keep growing!
一つ涙こぼれたら
When a single tear spills,
二つ両手をたたいてみつ数えてはじめよう
Clap both hands twice, count to three, and let's begin!
キミと入れば大丈夫
As long as I'm with you, it'll be alright.
弱音とほねて泣いたり 諦めかけたりすると
Sometimes crying or almost giving up,
振り返ればなのようにずっと強くなれたんだ
Looking back, I've grown so much stronger like a flower.
花びら一つずつじゃ 不意に折れそうでも ほら
Even if a single petal might easily snap, see,
支え合えたら 大切になれるよ
If we support each other, we can become precious.
手と手を合わせた 形は花びら
The shape of hands placed together is a cherry petal.
この気持ち 心のすきま越えて 届けるのさ
Crossing the gaps of our hearts, I will deliver this feeling!
変えられない私は 好きになってくれたこと
The unchangeable me—that you came to love me,
これからも後悔なんて させないように見ててね
Please keep watching so I never make you regret it from now on.
いじわるだったところよりも 強く大きくなったでしょ
Have I grown stronger and bigger than when I was teasing?
もっと キミは
More, you are...
ねぇ 想い出したんだろ
Hey, you remembered, didn't you?
そっと涙した日を
The days you quietly shed tears.
さあ数えてみようか
Come on, let's count them up,
これまで起こした奇跡を
The miracles that have happened so far.
ひとつとまらない足で
With a single unstopping step,
ふたつこえていく夢も
And dreams we surpass two by two,
みつかるつながる絆は
The bonds that we found and connected,
君とひろげてきたんだよ
I've expanded with you.
何度でも咲くように
Like flowers blooming time and time again,
続いてくこの物語 “ストーリー”
This story continues onward.
まだ見たことのない景色を探しに行こう
Let's go search for scenery we haven't seen yet.
花ひとつづつが小さくてもほら
Even if each flower is small, look—
支え合えたら桜になれるよ
If we support each other, we can become cherry blossoms.
ぼくらが育てた大きな木はまだ
The big tree we raised together is still...
これからも春風に乗って伸びていくのさ
Continuing to grow on the spring breeze from now on.
ひとつ涙こぼれたら
If a single tear spills over,
ふたつ両手を叩いて
Clap both hands twice,
みつ数えて始めよう
Count three and let's begin.
君がいれば大丈夫
As long as you're here, it'll be fine.
弱音と本音で泣いたりと
Crying with complaints and true feelings,
諦めかけた分かれ道 “ルート” も
Even the parting routes we almost gave up on—
振り返って笑うようにずっとなれたんだよ
Looking back, I've grown so much stronger.
それでは重大告知、どうぞ！
And now, for the major announcement—here it is!
自分らしさってなんだろう？
What does being myself mean?
上手く言えなかったわたしへ
To the me who couldn't say it well,
ひとりで探してきた
I searched for it alone,
仲間と見つけてきた
Found it together with my friends,
キミが見つけてくれた
And you found it for me.
さくらみこになるまでの物語
The story until I became Sakura Miko.
さくらみこ 1st Album 発売決定！！
Sakura Miko 1st Album Release Confirmed!!
あったけの花束を
With a warm bouquet of flowers,
思うままに歌ったこの歌が あなたの芽吹きになりますように。
May this song I sang as I pleased become a sprout for you.
エリート巫女アイドルストーリー
Elite Shrine Maiden Idol Story
2024.10.26 sat
さくらみこ 1st ソロライブ開催決定！！
Sakura Miko 1st Solo Live Confirmed!!
Sakura Miko 1st Live flower fantasista! 2024.10.26 sat ARIAKE ARENA
Sakura Miko 1st Live "flower fantasista!" - 2024.10.26 at Ariake Arena
さくらみこ活動開始
2018.08.01: Sakura Miko Activity Start
はじめてのYouTube配信
2018.08.28: First YouTube Stream
ホロライブ加入
2018.12.25: Joined Hololive
さくらみこ 2周年＆復帰LIVE
2020.10.21: 2nd Anniversary & Return Live
Miko Ch. チャンネル登録者 100万人突破
2021.04.30: Reached 1 Million Subscribers
さくらみこ3周年
2021.08.01: 3rd Anniversary
さくらみこ4周年
2022.08.01: 4th Anniversary
さくらみこ5周年
2023.08.01: 5th Anniversary
さくらみこ 1st EP heart♡connect リリース
2023.08.02: 1st EP "heart♡connect" Release
Miko Ch. チャンネル登録者 200万人突破
2024.04.09: Reached 2 Million Subscribers
さくらみこ 1st Album flower rhapsody 発表
2024.07.21: 1st Album "flower rhapsody" Announcement
このライブでみんなと分かち合いたい！
I want to share this live with everyone!
Sakura Miko みんな、ついてきて！
Sakura Miko: Everyone, follow me!
桜は咲き誇る 満開の舞台へ！
To the fully blooming stage where cherry blossoms thrive!
さくらみこ1stアルバムリリース＆1stソロライブ開催決定！
1st Album Release & 1st Solo Live Announcement!
はーい！ということね、
Hiii! So, you see...
なんとファーストアルバム発売と、
Not only is my 1st album releasing,
そしてみこの夢だったソロライブの開催が、ついに！決定しちゃいましたー！
but my dream of holding a solo live has finally been decided!
すごーい！
So amazing!
え、会場はですね、有明アリーナ！土曜日だよ、みんなすごいよ！
The venue is Ariake Arena! It's on a Saturday, everyone, that's amazing!
いや、ついにねみんなに使えられて、みこはもう胸がいっぱいだけどまだね本番じゃないからね。
Man, I'm finally able to reach everyone, and my heart is so full, but it's not the real show yet.
あれなんですけど、でも本当に本当にここまでたくさん応援してくれたみんなのおかげです。
But really, truly, this is all thanks to everyone who has cheered me on so much up to now.
あとみこの頑張り！スタッフさんの頑張り、いろんなね、ホロメンの支えもあって、ついにみこのひとつのね、大きな夢が叶うということで、
And Miko's hard work, the staff's hard work, and support from various members...
みんな嬉しいよね！めっちゃ嬉しいよね！
Everyone's happy, right? Super happy, right?!
いや本当にね、もうみこ活動して…
Man, truly, Miko's been active...
6周、
6th...
もうすぐ6周年でね。
Soon, it'll be our 6th anniversary.
もうずっとね、
For a long time now...
まあ、ひそかに夢見た時期から声を大きく、
Ever since I started dreaming in secret,
声を大きくして、
I wanted to make my voice louder,
「やりたい、やりたい」って言った時期からもいろんな時期がありましたけど、
and say, "I want to do this!"
いろんな時期から応援してくれた35P、
To the 35P who supported me through it all...
そして最近あの、見に来てくれたね35Pとか、
and to the 35P who've come to join us recently,
まだ35Pじゃないよって人にも、
even if you haven't been 35P for long,
もうめちゃくちゃ素晴らしいライブをお届けしたいなと思っておりますので、
I want to bring you into a truly wonderful live experience!
皆さんぜひ、
So everyone, please,
ぜひよろしくお願いします。
please look forward to it!
そしてアルバムもね、もう本当に頑張ります。
And as for the album, we've really worked hard.
頑張りましたから、みんなぜひね、あの買ってほしいですね。
We worked so hard, so I hope you'll all buy it!
ということで、じゃあ詳細をね、みんなに説明していけまーす。
So, let me explain the details to you all.
それでは、まず1つ目。
Now then, first off...
えっと、あ、そうだ。この後ね、
Oh right, after this,
あの最後に1曲歌うんで、皆さんぜひ最後までね、見てくださいね。
I'll be singing a new song at the very end,
それではまずアルバムの宣伝からでーす。
so first, let's start with the album announcement!
さくらみこ 1stアルバム『flower rhapsody』が、
Sakura Miko's 1st album, "flower rhapsody,"
2024年9月25日に発売決定！
will be released on September 25, 2024!
こちらのね、キービジュアルはのぶさわ先生、もちぷよ先生に、あの描き下ろしていただきましたー！
This jacket illustration was drawn by Nobusawa-sensei and Mochizuki-sensei!
めちゃくちゃ綺麗だよね。
It's so, so beautiful, right?
パッケージもね、あの、ちょっとこだわっておりまして、三方背ケースっていうのかな？
The package design is also quite unique, featuring a three-sided slipcase.
そう、めちゃくちゃこだわっているので、よろしくお願いします。
It's super special, so I hope you'll check it out!
そして、こんなに素敵なクリエイターの皆さまに参加していただきました！
And we had so many wonderful creators participate in this!
あの、なんとね、あの、3ヶ月連続リリースしてる曲は入ってるんですが、それ以外はね、全部新曲だよ、すごーい！
Out of all the tracks, the ones released over the past 3 months are included, but the rest are...
いやーもうやったね、頑張りましたね。
We really did our best!
はい、ということでこんな素敵なクリエイターの皆さまに参加していただきました。
So, thank you to all the wonderful creators who joined us.
通常版、数量限定版の2種類があります。
There will be two versions: standard and limited.
どちらも本日この後21時より各サイトで予約開始です。
Both will be available for pre-order starting at 9 PM tonight on various sites!
まずは通常版の紹介です。こちら！たどん！
First, let me introduce the standard edition, ta-da!
通常版の特典にはなんと全5種類のランダムクリアカードが1枚付いてきます。
The standard edition comes with one random clear card out of five possible designs!
このクリアカードにはなんと、数量限定でみこの直筆サインが入っているかもということでね、みんなぜひゲットしてみてくださいね。
And these clear cards might even feature a handwritten signature from Miko herself, so definitely try to get one!
さらに、各店舗でアルバムを買ってくださった方は、店舗別特典が付きます。全グッズだからね、お店ごとにいろんな特典があるのでみんなチェックしてね。
Furthermore, if you purchase the album at participating stores, you'll receive store-specific bonuses, so be sure to check those out as well!
そしてそして、数量限定版のご紹介です。
And now, let's introduce the limited edition!
いや、すごーい！めちゃくちゃえもいイラストですね。
It's so gorgeous and cute!
はい、こちら特典にはですね、
Here is what comes with the limited edition:
スペシャルブックレット、アクリルスタンド、hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEカード、そしてみこからのお手紙が入っております！もうこれまでのね、みこを支えてくれたみこぴーのみんなへ感謝を込めて書きました！
a special booklet, an acrylic stand, a holoLIVE OFFICIAL CARD GAME card, and a letter from Miko!
そしてこの限定版はね、もうパッケージもすごい豪華になってて、めちゃくちゃ可愛いのでね、ぜひゲットしてほしいです。
The packaging for this limited edition is super gorgeous and cute, so I really hope you'll get it!
限定版はホロライブプロダクション公式ショップで先着販売となります。ま、結構あるとは思うんですけども、ぜひね、お急ぎくださいませ。
It will be sold exclusively at the hololive production official shop, so be sure to grab yours quickly!
そして、封入特典のhololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEカードはなんと、みこの初のカード化になります！
And as a special bonus, the included holoLIVE OFFICIAL CARD GAME card will be Miko's very first card!
カードの詳細は、hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEの公式Xアカウントをフォローしてチェックしてくださいね。
Be sure to follow the official account of the holoLIVE OFFICIAL CARD GAME for details!
続いては、お待たせしました！ソロライブの情報です。まずはライブのキービジュアルを公開でーす！ドン！
And now, let's reveal the details for the live concert!
いやー可愛い！るるど先生に描き下ろしていただきましたよ。もうめちゃくちゃ神々しいよね。
It was drawn by Rurudo-sensei, and it's just so divine!
えっと、公演ハッシュタグは「#咲き誇るみこ」で、どんどんポストしていって盛り上げていってくださいね。
For the official hashtag, please use "#SakiHokoruMiko" to post and build the hype!
続いて、みんな気になるのは会場とチケット情報！今回のソロライブはなんと、有明アリーナでで開催します！
Now, the venue and ticket details for the concert, which will be held at Ariake Arena!
チケットはS席、A席、B席の3種類がございます。現地チケットの一次先行はこのあと21時から開始となりますので、ぜひチェックしてください。
There are three types of tickets: S, A, and B. Pre-orders for venue tickets begin tonight at 9 PM!
また今回はZAIKOで海外のみこぴー向けにも現地チケットを販売します。また配信チケットはSPWNとZAIKOで販売します。
Also, streaming tickets will be available via SPWN and ZAIKO, including for overseas fans.
こちらもね、あと21時から販売開始なので、会場に来れない人は配信でみこの雄姿を見に来てくださいね。
Ticket sales start at 9 PM tonight, so if you can't make it to the venue, please come see the show via stream!
各座席のエリアマップはこちら。S席は1階アリーナの前方、A席は1階の後方と2階、3階の前方。そしてB席は3階と4階に分かれております。
The seat map for Ariake Arena is as follows: S seats are in the front arena, A seats are in the rear arena and front stand, and B seats are in the stand (levels 3 and 4).
続いてお待たせしました、グッズ情報になります！グッズもこのあと21時より販売開始です。
Next up are the goodies! These will also go on sale starting at 9 PM tonight.
まずは応援セットのご紹介です。みこぴーライト、Tシャツ、タスキ風タオル、そしてセット特典のリストバンドが入っているセットになります。
First, the support set, which includes a MikoP penlight, T-shirt, towel, and wristband as a set bonus!
1万1300円ですね！
11,300 yen, you see!
えー、ま、こちらはですね、やっぱミコピイライトは、もうみんなね、絶対ゲットしなきゃいけないよねっていうのと、
Um, well, as for this one, as expected, everyone definitely has to get the MikoP Light, right?
どれもね、こだわり、こだわりを詰め込んだので、ぜひこれをね装着して来てくだいさいね！
and it's packed with so much attention to detail, so everyone please wear it and come!
それぞれのグッズは単品でも販売します。
Each piece of merchandise will also be sold individually.
今回、ミコピイはっぴも先行発送対象となります！やったー！
This time, the MikoP Happi is also eligible for early shipping! Yay!
はっぴ、作れ、作りたいて言ってましたからね。ついに作っちゃいましたよ！
I kept saying I wanted to make a happi, and finally, we made it!
え、ミコピイのみんなは当然フル装備で応援してくれるよね？はっぴは応援セットに含まれないので注意してください。
Um, all you MikoP will naturally support me fully equipped, right? Please note that the happi is not included in the support set.
さらに受注販売グッズも紹介します。
Furthermore, I'll introduce the made-to-order merchandise.
モチーフチャームと、えっと、とっても可愛い鯛焼きの形をしたポーチ付きブランケットです。
The motif charm and, um, a super cute taiyaki-shaped blanket with a pouch.
このモチーフチャームは、ミコのキミジャーに、あの太ももにね巻いているベルトをイメージして作ってるので、みんなもバッグやね、ポーチにつけてみてくださいね。
This motif charm is designed based on the belt Miko has tied around her thigh in Kimijara, so everyone please try attaching it to your bag or pouch.
続いて、クリアファイル＆缶バッジセットです。
Next is the clear file & pin badge set.
はい、アクリルペンライトスタンド、これめっちゃいいよね！めちゃくちゃ素敵です！
Yes, the acrylic penlight stand—this is super nice, right? This is extremely wonderful!
そしてタペストリーの紹介です。キミジャロ大きくタペストリーにしたので、これを飾ってライブ後の余韻に浸って欲しいなと思っております。
And here's the introduction to the tapestry. We made Kimijaro into a large tapestry, so I hope you'll display this and bask in the afterglow of the live.
最後に注意事項です。
Lastly, here are some precautions.
販売期間はこのあと21時から8月13日18時までです。
The sales period is from 21:00 onwards until August 13th at 18:00.
そして注意していただきたいのがグッズの発送時期についてです。
And what I'd like you to note is about the shipping time for the goods.
先行グッズは、え、ライブの前に届く予定なんですけど、受注販売グッズはライブの「後」にお届けします。
The early-bird goods are scheduled to arrive before the live, but made-to-order goods will be delivered *after* the live.
また、先行発送グッズはさくらみこファーストアルバム「フラワーラプソディ」
Also, early-shipping goods can only be purchased together with Sakura Miko's 1st album "Flower Rhapsody"
「フラワーラプソディ」以外の商品のと一緒に購入はできません。受注販売グッズを購入する場合は別会計でお買い求めください。
and no other items. When purchasing made-to-order goods, please purchase them in a separate transaction.
詳しくは公式X販売サイト、公式特設サイトをご確認ください！
Please check the official X sales site and official special site for details!
あー、ということで、告知は以上になりますよ、みんな大変だね！
Ah, with that, the announcements are over. Everyone must have a hard time!
ちょっと21時からね、もうかなりいろんな情報がね、ぶわーって出てみんな大変だと思うけど、まあどうぞよろしくお願いします！
From 21:00, quite a lot of information is going to come pouring out, and I think everyone will have a hard time, but please treat me well!
はー、ということでね、いやー、ちょっと駆け足でやりましたけれども、皆さんどうでしたか？
Phew, with that, man, I went through it rather quickly, but how was it everyone?
もう本当にミコはね、もう、なんだろう、もうすごいたくさん準備もね、頑張ってきましたし、もう痛くて痛くてしょうがなかったけれどね。
Truly, Miko has worked really hard preparing so much, and it hurt so much I couldn't help it, but...
まあ、みんなにね、黙ってないと、黙ってないとと思って、まあ、ここまで来ましたけど、
Well, thinking I had to keep it secret from everyone, I came this far, but...
なんかちょっとちょいちょいね、もうソロライブだろみたいなみんなやる気満々でね、いたりとかして嬉しいなって思って。
I felt happy seeing everyone all motivated, acting like "Is it a solo live already?" and all that.
もうミコピイはね、もうミコのことがね、とても大好きなんだと思いますからね。もう今泣いていると思うわ。
Since I think MikoP really, really loves Miko, I think you're crying right now.
ミコもね、あの、初めてライブできますよって言われたときはね、もう大泣きしましたね。うわ、やった、嬉しいなって。
When Miko was told, "You can have your first live," I cried my eyes out. "Wow, I did it, I'm so happy."
ミコ、まあ、アイドルとしてはね、まだまだだなっていっぱいね、いろんなホロメンがいる中でね、ミコってまだまだだよなってできないだろうなって思っていましたけど、
Miko thought, as an idol, I still have a long way to go, with various other Holomem around, Miko is still lacking and probably couldn't do it, but...
ついにね、もう、本当にみんなのおかげもあって大きく育って、ついに一花咲かせられるなという感じになっております。
finally, thanks to everyone's support, I've grown big and feel like I can finally make a flower bloom.
本当に応援してくれてるの、ありがとう。
Thank you so much for supporting me.
もうね、やば、泣きそうだよ、ちょっとどうしよう。
Man, I'm about to cry, what should I do?
はーい、ということでね、まだまだありますから、
Alright, with that, there's still more, so...
え、最後に、え、ファーストアルバムから新曲もなんと、お披露目します！
lastly, um, we will also unveil a new song from the 1st album!
じんさんに作詞作編曲曲を担当していただきました！そしてMVもこのあと公開します！すっごいに素敵になってるのでぜひ見てください！
Jin-san handled the lyrics, composition, and arrangement! And the MV will also be released right after this! It's turned out super wonderful, so please check it out!
本日24時に楽曲もリリースするので、みんな、アルバムリリースまでもたくさん聞いてね！
The song will also be released today at 24:00, so everyone, please listen to it a lot until the album release!
それでは、聞いてください！ 「DAI DAI DAI ファンタジスタ」！
Now then, please listen to it! "DAI DAI DAI Fantasista"!
nya ! hello ! !
Nya! Hello!!
the beautiful days ! !
The beautiful days!!
刮目しちゃってくれ！！
Open your eyes and look at me!!
please call 『 elite 』 !!
Please call "Elite"!!
さあ、待ってたはなしだ！始めちゃえ！
Now, it's the story we've been waiting for! Let's start!
今日も気ぃ引き締めてえや！で挑戦だ
Let's brace ourselves and take on the challenge today!
躊躇は厳禁 足踏みしないで
Hesitation is strictly forbidden, don't just mark time!
一緒に「せぇの！」でもっと前に行こうね？
Together on "One, two!", let's go even further ahead, okay?
さあ、なんだかなっちゃえ！飛び込んで
Come on, whatever happens, dive right in!
なんたってジッとしたって人生は冒険だ
After all, staying still won't change that life is an adventure!
こんがらがったらまたわからないぞ
If you get all tangled up, you won't understand again!
道のりは困難だ！なんなんだ！
The path is difficult! What on earth!
上等だ！ダンダンダン！
Bring it on! Dun, dun, dun!
メゾメゾしちゃって
Fretfully hesitating,
気持ちに「待った」しちゃって
Putting a "hold" on your feelings,
にゃ！hello！！
Nya! Hello!!
the beautiful days！
The beautiful days!
刮目しちゃってくれ！
Look closely at me!
please call『elite』！！
Please call "elite"!!
さあ、待ったなしだ！始めちゃえ！
Now then, no more waiting! Let's start!
今日も気合い引き締めてえや！で挑戦だ
Today too, pulling it together nicely, let's challenge it!
躊躇は厳禁 足踏みしてないで
Hesitation is strictly forbidden, without even stepping,
一緒に「せぇの！」でもっと前に行こうね？
Together with a "Sei!", let's go even further ahead, okay?
さあ、なんとかしちゃえ！飛び込んで
Now, somehow or another, let's jump in!
なんたってジッとしたって人生は冒険だ
No matter what they say, even if it's like that, life is an adventure!
こんがらかったらまたわかんないぞ
If you get tangled up, you still won't know, right?
道打ちは困難だ！なんなんだ！
Doing it right is difficult! What, what is this?!
上等だ！ダンダンダン！
Top-notch! Dandandan!
メモメモしちゃって
Memos and memos, doing it like that,
気持ちに「待った」しちゃって
Turning feelings into a "Wait", doing it like that,
あれ？一体全体どうしたんだ！？
Huh? What on earth happened?!
絶体絶命！？
Dire straights?!
君たちには涙は似合わないね！
Tears don't suit you guys at all!
大大大大冒険に飛び出そうぜ！
Let's fly out into a grand, grand adventure!
良いじゃんねぇ！
Ain't it great?!
大大大大失敗も重ねて成長して
Growing by piling up even huge, huge failures,
happyなfeel soで君と笑い話にしよう
With a happy feel so, let's make it a smiling talk with you!
大大大大問題も吹き飛ばせ！
Blow away even grand, grand problems!
いつか大大大大団円の素敵な結末へ
Toward the wonderful conclusion of an ever grand, grand circle,
please me！！
Please me!!
さあ、付いてきて？
Now, won't you come along?
進め！前代未聞のnew world！
Advance! To an unprecedented new world!
がちな間違いっ...てまた墓穴も掘ってる
Looking away and making mistakes again, digging up graves too
勉強！勉強！
Studying! Studying!
(はいはいはい、知ってます。待て、なんか違ってる！)
(Yes, yes, yes, I know it. Wait, something's wrong!)
ぶっちゃけ有識者の皆様に感謝してます！
I'm truly grateful to all the knowledgeable people who figured it out!
nice comment's待ってんぞ
Waiting for nice comments
(あ～ね)
(Ah, geez)
ウジウジしちゃって心にロックしちゃって
Fidgeting and doing it, locked in my heart,
ほら、だんだんだんだんダウンしちゃって
Look, step by step, down and doing it
絶体絶命！？
Dire straights?!
君たちには笑顔が足りないね！
You guys don't have enough smiles!
大大大大大好きじゃ収まらない！
A grand, grand favorite is just too much to contain!
良いじゃんねぇ！
Ain't it great?!
最大最高レベルにガチの全力で！
With serious effort at the maximum level,
もっと欲しがっちゃって？豪快に贅沢に行こう
Wanting even more, let's go for bold luxury!
全然前進しないなんて凹んじゃったってなら
"It's not advancing at all," and if you say you're depressed,
なら全身全霊エンジン全開
Then, body and soul, engines fully open,
本気(マジ)の全力で！
With true all-out power!
にゃ！hello！！さあbeautifulに！
Nya! Hello!! Now, to be beautiful!
意気込んで進め！freedom way！
Pushing forward with enthusiasm, freedom way!
(wow wow)
乗り遅れんなよ皆！
Don't miss the ride, everyone!
(wow wow)
声を聴かせてくれ！yeah！
Let me hear your voice! Yeah!
(wow wow)
歌おう声高らかに
Let's sing out loud!
(wow wow)
ベイビーベイビーベイビーベイビー
Baby, baby, baby, baby!
なんていうか…
What should I call it...
あぁ、なんだかちょっと言い表せない
Ah, somehow I can't quite put it into words.
一人ぼっちで見てた景色を
The scenery I used to watch all by myself,
今はきっとあなたと冒険している！
Now I'm surely adventuring with you!
大大大大大大大大大大大好きじゃ収まらない！
Grand, grand, grand, grand, grand, grand, grand, grand favorite is just too much to contain!
だから最大最高レベルにガチの全力で！
So with true all-out power at the maximum highest level!
にゃ！hello！！届けちゃうぜ！
Nya! Hello!! Let's make it reach!
ずーっと大冒険しようyeah！！
Let's keep adventuring, yeah!!
大大大大問題も吹き飛ばせ！
Blow away even grand, grand problems!
いつか大大大大団円の素敵な結末へ
Toward the wonderful conclusion of an ever grand, grand circle,
please me！！
Please me!!
さあ、付いてきて？
Now, won't you come along?
進め！前代未聞のnew world！
Advance! To an unprecedented new world!
がちな間違いっ...てまた墓穴も掘ってる
Looking away and making mistakes again, digging up graves too
勉強！勉強！
Studying! Studying!
ぶっちゃけ有識者の皆様に感謝してます！
I'm truly grateful to all the knowledgeable people who figured it out!
nice comment's待ってんぞ
Waiting for nice comments
ウジウジしちゃって心にロックしちゃって
Fidgeting and doing it, locked in my heart,
ほら、だんだんだんだんダウンしちゃって
Look, step by step, down and doing it
絶体絶命！？
Dire straights?!
君たちには笑顔が足りないね！
You guys don't have enough smiles!
大大大大大好きじゃ収まらない！
A grand, grand favorite is just too much to contain!
良いじゃんねぇ！
Ain't it great?!
みんな！ライブ絶対見にこいよなー！
Everyone, let's definitely make it come true tonight!
Thank you！
Thank you!